<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tips on Rafael Tieppo</title>
    <link>/tags/tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tips on Rafael Tieppo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 &lt;a href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#39;&gt;Licensed CC:By-NC-SA&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conditional in Python: map vs loop</title>
      <link>/post/2021_12_02_python_map_loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021_12_02_python_map_loop/</guid>
      <description>Usually I need to classify some kind of data. Some weeks ago, I had a huge file with dates and precipitation, and one of the tasks was classify each day as ten-day. Thus, each month was divided in three sections as follow:
 from day 01 up to 10 is *ten-day 01* from day 11 up to 20 is *ten-day 02* from day 21 up to 31 is *ten-day 03*  Most of time I had used loops (Python language), however this time the process took a little bit slow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ambiente virtual em Python</title>
      <link>/post/2021_07_27_python_env/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021_07_27_python_env/</guid>
      <description>Um dos objetivos do ambiente virtual é auxiliar no gerenciamento das dependências exigidas nos projetos. Um exemplo prático seria a necessidade de testar um código em uma versão antiga de um determinado pacote (ou biblioteca), sendo que na sua máquina esteja instalada a versão mais recente deste pacote. Para evitar algum possível conflito de versões, e possíveis danos no seu sistema operacional, é possível criar um ambiente virtual que deixará isolado os pacotes antigos necessários.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes in python objects</title>
      <link>/post/2020_12_31_pythonchanges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020_12_31_pythonchanges/</guid>
      <description>I am enthusiast programmer, thus I am no a professional. I wanna getting better and some times I write some notes to improve my English and programming skills. Certainly you will find some mistakes in the text and programming concepts in this post, I am sorry, I am trying.
Lets go to what matter now!
The word change is ambiguous in Python, it means that we have two distinct types of &amp;ldquo;change&amp;rdquo; in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Python - Numpy and Pandas library</title>
      <link>/post/2020_12_30_pandas_tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020_12_30_pandas_tips/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Saving time for cleaning, tidying and processing data is quite useful in data science. It means that you can get more time to analyses and think about solutions.
If I working Data Science with Python, usually I am using Pandas and Numpy library. It is a great library with a lot smart functions. However, sometimes I forget some functions and write my own functions to solve calculations. For practicing it is cool, but it spends some time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python beginner tips</title>
      <link>/post/2018_12_16_pythontips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018_12_16_pythontips/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I spent around 4 years working with R, and I can say that R is amazing. However, I decided to start a new stage in my professional life, and a need came, a multi proposal language. My option was Python, because It provides have data science tools, and has a huge support for others applications.
After some months, studying in my free time, I would like to share some code that I learned (from several sources).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
