<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>datascience on Rafael Tieppo</title>
    <link>/categories/datascience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in datascience on Rafael Tieppo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/datascience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Julian date with python 3</title>
      <link>/post/2018_12_01_juliandate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018_12_01_juliandate/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The work in data science must be tidy. A simple file name can help you to save a lot of time. For instance, if you have a series of satellite images from LANDSAT 8, the files are ordered by Julian date:
rt@rt-d5567:~/Documents/$ find -name &#39;*305*.TIF&#39; ./LO82280702018305CUB00_B3.TIF ./LO82280702018305CUB00_B9.TIF ./LO82280702018305CUB00_B5.TIF  If you did not realize, note that after 2018 there are three numbers 305. The number 305 means the 305th day of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histogram and Barplot with Python</title>
      <link>/post/2018_11_26_barhistpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018_11_26_barhistpy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Some people make a small confusion with histogram and barplots. So in this post we intend to provide some points about both of them.
Let&amp;rsquo;s supose that we have a sample from 200 persons, and we need to check the age distribution, so we can produce a histogram (Figure 1).
# creating data DF = pd.DataFrame({&amp;#34;A&amp;#34; : np.random.normal(30, 0.75, 200)}) # plot plt.figure(figsize=(8, 5)) plt.hist(DF[&amp;#34;A&amp;#34;], bins = 10, color=&amp;#39;steelblue&amp;#39;, alpha = 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordenar dados INMET</title>
      <link>/post/141211_inmetdataorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/141211_inmetdataorder/</guid>
      <description>Introdução Em algum momento da graduação ou pós-graduação, você já trabalhou com séries históricas de clima. No seu estudo, provavelmente você se deparou com o desafio de organizar e analisar, arquivos que comumente atingem 10000 linhas.
Uma das fontes mais comuns para obtenção de dados climáticos é o INMET. Contudo, os arquivos que são obtidos pelo site do INMET, não possuem uma formatação das mais práticas (Figura 1).
Repare que para cada dia registrado duas linhas são ocupadas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>